ami.com 2019-07-31

# American Megatrends International LLC - Privacy Policy

* * *

This Privacy Policy applies only to our website ami.com.

At American Megatrends International LLC (hereafter known as “AMI”) we respect your privacy.

AMI only collects business related personal data that is used for business communication and operations with your company; for example, to perform accounting, auditing, billing, marketing, sales and other business-related activities.

## I. General Information

### Data Privacy Rights Specific to Residents of the European Union

If you are in the EEA (European Economic Area), please reference the American Megatrends International GmbH Privacy Policy (<https://ami.de/datenschutz.html>). You may also contact our American Megatrends International GmbH Office at Truderinger Strasse 283, 81825 Munich, Germany or email winfried@ami.de concerning our Privacy Policy for Residents of the European Union.

**The AMI website located at https://ami.com/ is not to be used by residents of the EEA. If you are a resident of the EEA, please visit<https://ami.de/>.**

### Personal Data Collected

AMI defines Personal data as any data about an identified or identifiable natural person, or any information that in combination with other non-personal information can reasonably be used to identify a natural person.

As a part of AMI’s standard business operations with your company, AMI collects personal data, so it may provide services, respond to requests, offer customer support, and fulfill legal, contractual or financial obligations to your company. The type of personal data AMI collects from you depends upon the type of interactions you have with AMI websites and services, including the context of your interactions with AMI, the choices you make (including privacy settings) as well as the products and services you use.

You may choose to voluntarily give personal data to AMI directly in a variety of methods such as through our websites, products, online services, software, apps, tools, and other online and offline services and functionality we provide. When you subscribe to a newsletter, create an account, make a purchase or request information from AMI, we will ask for information related to your business, such as contact name, email address, phone number, company name, billing address, shipping address communication information, company financial information and account ID or credentials in order to fulfill your request. If you attend a trade show or marketing event, or otherwise contact us, you may also voluntarily provide similar personal data.

We may also collect information relating to your use of our websites and our services through the use of various technologies. For example, when you visit our websites, we may log certain information that your browser sends, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access time, and referring web site addresses. We may collect information about the pages you view within our websites and other actions you take while visiting us. In addition, some of our services include technologies that allow us to collect certain information about product use.

We may also collect information that pertains to your company, from other sources, such as vendors. When we do so, we ask the vendors to confirm that the information was legally acquired and that we have the right to obtain it from them before we use it.

### Security Measures

AMI protects the personal data you provide us. Access to personal data is limited to people who need it to perform their job functions and have a need to know. Authorized third-party agents may also need access to some of the personal data. For example, if AMI needs to ship products to customers, it shares the customer's name and address with the shipping company. AMI only provides third-party agents with the minimum amount of information needed to complete the requested transaction.

### How We Use Your Personal Data

We collect and use your personal data to operate our business; for example, to perform accounting, auditing, billing, reconciliation, and collection activities. Other business purposes that depend on use of your personal information include crime or fraud monitoring and prevention, protecting our legal rights, and performing contractual obligations. We also use personal information to contact you to advertise, market and sell AMI products and services in accordance with your communication preferences. As an example, we collect and use your personal data, for the following purposes: 

  * To communicate and provide you with the information you have requested;
  * Process, fulfill and follow up on transactions and requests for products, services, support, and information;
  * Customize the content, products and services that are offered to you;
  * Contact you with information about AMI and affiliated third-parties;
  * Communicate, interact and build our relationship with you for purposes such as marketing and product support;
  * Verify your authority to enter and use our services;
  * Engage in market research and analysis;
  * Measure, analyze and improve our products and services, the effectiveness and user experience of our websites, and our advertising and marketing;
  * Consider an employment application;
  * Comply with legal requirements;
  * Provide targeting advertising, including the use of re-targeting technology; and
  * Deter, detect, and prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities.

We may link or combine information we collect from multiple sources to provide better service to you and to improve our products and services.

### Why You are Required to Provide Personal Data

In general, your provision of any personal data or granting of consent to a processing activity is entirely voluntary. However, there are certain circumstances in which AMI cannot act without processing certain personal data, for example to process your orders, to assist you with use of our products or services, or to provide access to a web offering or newsletter. In these cases, it will not be possible for AMI to provide what you request without the relevant personal information. In some circumstances, AMI may need to terminate your ability to use the services without access to your personal data.

### Sharing of Your Personal Data

AMI is a global organization with business processes, management structures and technical systems that are worldwide. As such, we may share data about you with other AMI entities and transfer it to countries in the world where we do business in connection with the uses identified in this Privacy Policy. Our procedures are designed to provide a globally consistent level of protection for personal information by all AMI entities.

We share personal data for reasons like fulfilling orders, processing payments, preparing and sending advertising campaigns, or as otherwise necessary to complete any transaction or provide any product or service you have requested or authorized. Where sharing takes place, we use controls to establish protections for the personal data that is shared. Sharing may take place with affiliates and subsidiaries; suppliers working on our behalf; law enforcement or government official and for purposes consistent with this Privacy Policy including to protect our customers; to protect lives; to maintain the security of AMI products and services; and to protect our rights and property.

We may disclose personal information as part of a contemplated or actual corporate transaction such as a reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings).

Where you post information to our wikis, forums, blogs, message boards, chat rooms, websites or other social networking environments, your information will be shared with audiences within those platforms.

We may share your personal data based on a good faith belief that such disclosure is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, or situations involving potential threats to the safety of any person. We may use your personal data as evidence in litigation in which we are involved, to protect the rights or safety of any person or entity, to respond to a judicial process or valid government inquiry or as otherwise required by law.

### Where We Process Personal Data

If you choose to provide us with information, including personal data, you understand that we are storing this and/or transferring it to AMI's locations and systems in the United States and possibly to the locations and systems of AMI's affiliates or service providers around the world.

### Retention of Personal Data

Retention periods can vary significantly based on the type of information and how it is used and our retention periods are based on criteria that include legally mandated retention periods, pending or potential litigation, our intellectual property or ownership rights, contract requirements, operational directives or needs, and historical archiving. We retain personal information for the period necessary to: Provide requested services, as needed to comply with legal obligations (e.g. maintaining opt-out lists to fulfill advertising choices or to comply mandatory record retention or legal hold requirements), as agreed in an individual consent, to resolve disputes, and to otherwise fulfill the purposes, rights and obligations outlined in this Privacy Notice.

### Websites

This Privacy Policy covers the information practices of how your personal data is collected from our websites, including how AMI uses, shares and secures the personal data you provide.

AMI may provide weblinks to other third-party websites and applications over which AMI does not have control. Such weblinks do not constitute an endorsement by AMI and AMI does not control the content or privacy policies or practices of such third-party websites. Any access to and use of such linked websites is governed by the privacy policies of those third parties' websites. AMI encourages users to review the privacy policies posted on all third-party websites prior to submitting any personal data to that third-party website.

### Controller

The data controller is American Megatrends International LLC, a Georgia corporation located at 5555 Oakbrook Parkway, Suite 200, Norcross, GA, 30093, USA. If you have any questions on this Privacy Policy or any of our data processing practices, please contact privacy@ami.com or write to American Megatrends International LLC at 5555 Oakbrook Parkway, Suite 200, Norcross, GA, 30093, USA, c/o General Counsel. Our EU representative per article 27 GDPR is American Megatrends International GmbH, Truderinger Strasse 283, 81825 Munich, Germany.

### Your Rights as a Data Subject

_Access, correction, deletion of personal data:_ Where applicable by law, you may request the personal data AMI holds about you and the correction or deletion, also known as the right-to-be-forgotten, of such personal data at any time. AMI can only delete your personal data if there is no statutory obligation or prevailing right of AMI to retain it. In addition, if you request deletion of your personal data you will not be able to continue to use any AMI products or services that require the use of your personal data. Please note that any deletion requests will have no effect on past processing of personal data up to the point in time of your deletion requests.

_Request personal data in a portable format:_ If AMI uses your personal data based on your consent or to perform a contract with you, you may further request from AMI a copy of the personal data in a portable format that you have provided to AMI and where processing is carried out by automated means.

_Restriction of processing and right to object:_ You can also request that AMI restrict (without deleting) further processing of your personal data: (i) if you state that your personal data is incorrect, for as long as we need to verify the accuracy of the personal data, (ii) if there is no legal basis for AMI to process your personal data and you demand that AMI restricts your personal data from further processing instead of deleting it, (iii) if AMI no longer needs your personal data but you as data subject claim that you require AMI to retain such data in order to establish, exercise or defend a legal claim, or (iv) where AMI processes your personal data on the basis of its legitimate interest as further detailed in Section II and you object to the processing of your personal data for as long as it is required to review whether AMI has a prevailing interest or legal obligation to process your personal data.

Please send any such requests to privacy@ami.com.

### Right to Log A Complaint

If you believe that AMI is not processing your personal data in accordance with the requirements set out herein or applicable data protection laws, you can log a complaint with the relevant supervisory authority at any time by contacting us via our [Data Privacy Inquiry Form](https://ami.com/data-privacy-inquiry-form/) or e-mail us at privacy@ami.com.

### Use of AMI Websites by Minors

For these purposes, we define a "minor" to mean an individual who is under the age of majority in the territory in which they are resident. AMI recognizes the privacy interests of minors and we encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in their children's online activities and interests. We do not knowingly collect personal information from minors without proper consent from a parent or legal guardian. AMI's websites are not intended for minors and AMI does not target our websites to minors. If you believe that we may have collected personal information from a minor without the requisite consent, please let us know via email at privacy@ami.com.

## II. Details on Processing and Legal Basis for Processing

### a. Where AMI Uses Your Personal Data Based On Law

AMI is permitted to process your personal data under applicable data protection law as follows:

Providing the requested information or services. If you request information on our products or services on behalf of your company, order our products and/or services or become our business partner, we typically ask you to provide your personal contact information such as name, company name, business email address, business telephone number, company name and address, job title, role. If payment is to be made to AMI, we ask you to provide company financial and billing information, such as company billing name and address, company tax identification number, company credit information, company bank details or other payment information. We use the personal data only to process your order or to provide the requested product and/or service. Specifically, this includes: taking the necessary steps prior to entering into a contract, confirming your opening of an account, responding to your inquiries, processing or providing customer feedback and support, providing you with billing or shipping information, sending you (i) notice of payments, (ii) information about changes to our services, (iii) other related notices and (iv) disclosures as required by law.

If you participate in tutorials and trainings or use learning tools provided by AMI, we may also ask you about your professional qualifications, relevant experience and education. AMI may also track your learning progress in order to make this information available to you.

General Business Relationship Communications. AMI communicates on a regular basis by email with users of our services. For resolving partner, customer or user complaints or inquire into suspicious transactions we may also communicate by phone. Generally, users cannot opt out of these communications, which are not marketing-related but required for the relevant business relationship. With regard to marketing-related communication by phone or e-mail, AMI will (i) if legally required, only provide you with such communications after you have opted in, and (ii) provide you the opportunity to opt out if you do not want to receive further marketing-related types of communication from us. You can opt out of these at any time by following this unsubscribe link.

### b. Where AMI Uses Your Personal Data Based On AMI's Legitimate Interest

In addition to the use instances under applicable law, the use instances below constitute a legitimate interest of AMI to process or use your personal data. If you do not agree with this approach, you may object to AMI's processing or use of your personal data as set out below under the ‘right to object" heading.

Questionnaires and surveys. AMI may invite you to participate in questionnaires and surveys. These questionnaires and surveys are generally designed in a way that they can be answered without any personal data. Nonetheless, if you enter personal data in a questionnaire or survey, AMI may use such personal data to improve its services.

Usage Data. In the course of providing our services to you, we may collect, use, process and store usage data such as number of sessions, number of users, page views, number of page views per session, average session duration, bounce rate, percentage of new sessions, language of user, country, city, new versus returning users, browser type, operating system, internet service provider, IP address, screen resolution size, service used, service version number and mobile device brand. The usage data is collected and processed in order to create and compile anonymized, aggregated datasets and/or statistics about the services for the following purposes: (a) to maintain and improve the performance and integrity of our services, (b) to understand which services are most commonly deployed and preferred by customers and how customers interact with our services, (c) to identify the types of services that may require additional maintenance or support, and (d) to comply with regulatory, legislative and/or contractual requirements. Please note that such aggregated datasets and statistics will not enable you or any living individual to be identified. For more details on the usage data collected please refer to our Cookie Policy at [ami.com/cookie-policy](https://ami.com/cookie-policy/).

Supplemental Usage Data. In the course of providing products to you and your company, we may collect supplemental usage data. Supplemental usage data consists of debug dumps and system logs from AMI products and services that assist us in troubleshooting issues within the said product or the company’s IT environment. The debug dumps and systems logs include, but not limited to, IP address(es), company identifier information, browser type, browser language and locale, operating system, device type, date and time of request, user id, technical information and product information. The supplemental usage data may be used to provide you with better service, more detailed and higher quality returned data, support service troubleshooting and performance improvement.

Product and company news/request feedback. If we have an existing business with you, AMI may inform you about our products or services (including webinars, seminars or events) which are similar or relate to such products and services you have already purchased or used from AMI. Furthermore, where you have attended a webinar, seminar or event of AMI or purchased products or services from AMI, AMI may contact you for feedback regarding the improvement of the relevant webinar, seminar, event, product or service.

Personal data transferred in an acquisition. If we are acquired by or merged with another entity, if all or part of our assets are acquired, or in response to a bankruptcy proceeding, we may transfer your information to the acquiring entity for purposes that are similar to those for which it was originally acquired.

Data received from AMI entities. Our global entities may enter business contact details of prospects (such as name, company, title, company address, e-mail and phone number) which have expressed an interest in receiving information about AMI and our services into AMI's customer relation management system.

Data received from third parties. Our business partners may register leads with us in which they provide the business contact details of prospects (such as name, company, title, company address, e-mail and phone number) which have expressed an interest in receiving information about AMI and our services. We may also use such personal data to assist our business partners in responding to your request.

We also may receive personal data from third parties such as marketing or advertising companies or organizers of events that provide us with such information as a part of their relationship with us. Such data could include contact details (such as name, company, title, company address, e-mail and phone number) and we use that information for evaluating a potential business relationship with you or for combining the information with personal data that we may have already collected about you.

Right to object. You may object to AMI using your personal data for the purposes set forth in this subsection b at any time by sending your request to privacy@ami.com. If you do so, AMI will cease using your personal data for such purposes and remove it from its systems unless AMI is permitted to use such personal data for another purpose set out in this Privacy Policy or AMI determines and demonstrates a compelling legitimate interest to continue processing your personal data.

### c. Where AMI Uses Your Personal Data Voluntarily Provided

For non-EAA (European Economic Area) users, in addition to the use cases under applicable law and legitimate interests set forth above, AMI may use your personal data after you have voluntarily provided your personal data to AMI.

News about AMI's Products and Services. Where you have voluntarily provided personal data, we may use your name, email address, telephone number, job title and basic information about your employer (name, address, and industry) in order to keep you up-to-date on the latest product announcements, software updates, software upgrades, special offers, and other information about AMI's products and services and events (including marketing-related newsletters).

Events. If you register for an AMI event, seminar, or webinar, we may share basic participant information (typically your name, company, title, and email address) with other participants of the same event, seminar, or webinar for the purpose of communication and the exchange of ideas with your consent. We may also ask you to consent to sharing your participant information with sponsors of that event.

In addition, we may ask for information about special dietary requirements or other health/impairment information in connection with the registration for, and provision of access to an event or seminar. Any such information is voluntary. We may not be able to take any respective precautions if you choose not to provide such information.

Employment application. If you apply for a job (eg via our website), we may require you to submit additional personal information as well as a resume or curriculum vitae and other information. We encourage you to limit the personal data to the information necessary to enable us to evaluate your suitability for the position for which you are applying.

Forums and social media. You have the option to participate in blogs, forums and social media networks which may be offered by AMI or linked to our websites. If you choose to participate, you are required to register and create a user profile. User profiles provide the option to display personal information about you to other users, including, but not limited to your name, photo, social media accounts, postal address, email address, telephone number, personal interests, skills, and basic information about your company. All of the information you post will be available to all visitors to our websites. AMI is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums. You are not permitted to provide any personal information about other data subjects in those forums and blogs, and we also encourage you to limit any personal information about yourself to a minimum.

### Revocation of A Consent Granted Hereunder

You may at any time object to, opt out and withdraw a consent granted hereunder by e-mailing privacy@ami.com. If you would like to unsubscribe from our newsletters or no longer receive email communication from AMI, then please [click here](https://ami.com/unsubscribe/) and input your email address.

In case of withdrawal, AMI will cease processing the relevant personal data which was based on consent unless we have legal justification to reject the withdrawal. If AMI is required to retain your personal data for legal reasons, your personal data will be restricted from further processing and retained for the term required by law. Please note that any withdrawal has no effect on past processing of personal data up to the point in time of your withdrawal. Furthermore, if use of our products or services requires your consent and you have withdrawn your consent, AMI will no longer be able to provide the products or services to you.

## III. Cookies

If you use our websites, we may use various website navigation information including tracking technologies such as cookies and web beacons to collect and store information from you. Website navigation information includes: standard information from your Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), language choices, time zone, your Internet Protocol (IP) address, actions you take on our websites, URL and page metadata, installation data (such as the operating system type and application version), system crash information, system activity and hardware settings. We may also automatically collect and store certain information in activity logs such as: details of how you use our websites, your search queries, and your IP address.

For more details please see our "Cookie Policy" at [ami.com/cookie-policy](https://ami.com/cookie-policy/).

## IV. Changes to Privacy Policy

AMI reserves the right to change, modify, add or remove portions of this Privacy Policy from time to time to accurately reflect our practices. Such changes, modifications, additions or deletions are performed at the sole discretion of AMI. Our policy is to alert you that changes have been made by indicating on the Privacy Policy the date it was last updated. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Notice to stay informed about how we collect, use, and share personal data.

## V. How To Contact Us

If you have questions about AMI’s Privacy Policy, please contact us via our [Data Privacy Inquiry Form](https://ami.com/data-privacy-inquiry-form/) or e-mail us at privacy@ami.com. If you wish to review or change information gathered about you via an AMI Website, but do not know how, please contact us via our [Data Privacy Inquiry Form](https://ami.com/data-privacy-inquiry-form/) or email us at privacy@ami.com and we will assist you.

American Megatrends International LLC  
5555 Oakbrook Parkway, Suite 200  
Norcross, Georgia, 30093, U.S.A.  
770-246-8600  
privacy@ami.com

February 11, 2019
